CURRICULUM VITAE



Personal information

Surname(s) / First name(s)

Address(es)

Telephone(s)

Email(s)

Date of birth

Oprisan Andrei

str Magura, nr 24, 550317, Sibiu, jud Sibiu, Romania

+40 748 75 75 95

andrei.oprisan@obsidian-innovations.com

April 17, 1982

Personal skills and competences

SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

Andrei has 14 years of experience in software industry and academia, acting as product manager, software developer, architect and researcher, with almost 5 years in the data security field and 5 years writing Business Intelligence SaaS applications.

Andrei's area of work led him to design and develop data destruction software solutions and Business Intelligence SaaS applications, handle a variety of technical tasks ranging from back-end services architecture and implementation to developing front-end GUIs. Deep work in back-end services made him a Guru on integration strategies with different third party service providers. While working in data security area he was involved in the achievement of industry top security certificates.

In the last several years Andrei has been consulting companies and startups on software development services, with the last year focused on Business Intelligence solutions for energy management.

Additional information can be found in his LinkedIn profile

http://www.linkedin.com/in/aoprisan

MOTHER TONGUE

Romanian

English (advanced)

Key projects and accomplishments

DRESSPANIC, 2014

http://www.dresspanic.com

Designed and developed the concept and implementation of a web application with the social network and marketplace aspects for fashion followers, stylists and other "what to wear" female questioners. Scala, Play 2, JavaScript, Amazon S3, MongoDB, Loginza, Tradedoubler.

FORESTRYCLOUD, 2014

http://www.forestrycloud.com

Designed and developed the concept and implementation of a web application for online forest inventory system. Scala, Play 2, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, GeoServer, OpenLayers, Paytrail. Mobile app with restricted features using Titanium by Appcelerator.

SMEEBI, 2013

http://www.smeebi.com

Designed and developed the concept and implementation of a complex business intelligence web application. Details provided below.

SCALAEX MUSIC PLAYER, 2013

https://github.com/ssemakin/scfx-player

A maturity test for the JavaFX 2.x based ScalaFX framework.

THRIVEREPORTER, 2011

http://www.thrive-reporter.com/

Data visualization and reporting tool for analyzing securities markets trading activity. JavaFX 1.x, Scala, JasperReports.

OBSIDIAN INNOVATIONS, 2011

http://www.obsidian-innovations.com

IT consultancy company. Team member and co-founder. Details provided below.

BLANCCO DATA ERASURE 5, 2009

http://www.blancco.com/us/products/total-data-erasure/blancco-5/

Based on the experience of the prior versions, bootstrapped and developed the first releases of a new generation data destruction software solution. Details provided below.

Web-based E-Learning platform, 2006 Graduation work for my Bachelor degree, built with a team of three people, using cutting edge technologies for that date, such as Asp.Net 2.0, Ajax.Net, Dependency Injection, object relational mapping.

Additional information

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Literature, jogging, hiking, traveling, programming languages

Recommendations

SMEEBI, BLANCCO

SMEEBI, OLAPCON

BLANCCO

BLANCCO

UNIVERSITY OF JOENSUU

Rob Connell, CEO of Smeebi, +358 505 851 302

Mika Hurskainen, Chairman of Smeebi, +358 40 7576 713

Lasse Riekkinen, Director of R&D at Blancco, +358 50 4956 615

Mikko Koponen, COO at Blancco, +358 40 6879 505

Simo Juvaste, Deputy Head of CS Department, +358 50 380 3416

Education

TITLE OF QUALIFICATION AWARDED

OHOMNIZMION

LITLE OF GRADUATE WORK

Master of Science in Computer Science

September 2006–September 2008

Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Science, University of Joensuu, Joensuu, Finland «Aspect Oriented Implementation of Design Patterns using Metadata »

ftp://cs.joensuu.fi/pub/Theses/2008_MSc_Oprisan_Andrei.pdf

TITLE OF QUALIFICATION AWARDED
DATES
ORGANIZATION

Diploma Engineer, Computer Engineering

September 2001-June 2006

Universitatea Tehnică "Gh. Asachi" din Iași

«Web-based E-Learning platform»

Work experience

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD

DATES

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

TYPE OF BUSINESS OR SECTOR

MAIN ACTIVITIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Senior Scala Software Engineer

April 2015–Present Time

Eloquentix Ltd, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, United States

Scala Software Development

- Software design and development using agile techniques, functional and object-oriented programming of distributed micro-services
- Database REST access services
- Working with remote teams
- Test Driven Development
- Development primarily with Scala, Java, Play 2.x, Docker, Postgresql, Hibernate

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD

DATES

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

TYPE OF BUSINESS OR SECTOR

MAIN ACTIVITIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Senior Software Engineer

April 2014-Present Time

WEBfactory GmbH, Buchen, Germany

Software Development of Business Intelligence Systems

- Software design and development using agile techniques, object-oriented programming
- Front-end architecture and development
- Reports design and development
- Automation of deployment routines
- OLAP cubes configuration and data import services
- Development primarily with C#, F#, Javascript, Typescript, Durandal, Knockout, Underscore, Asp.Net MVC and Web API, .Net Reactive Extensions, Microsoft SQL Server, Analysis Services and Reporting Services

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD
DATES

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

TYPE OF BUSINESS OR SECTOR

MAIN ACTIVITIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Software Architect and CTO, Co-Founder

December 2011-Present Time

Smeebi Ltd (subsidiary of Olapcon Oy), Espoo and Joensuu, Finland

Software Development of Business Intelligence Systems

- Software project management, design and development using agile techniques, functional and object-oriented programming
- Technologies evaluation and business development
- Back-end architecture and development
- Integration strategies with different service providers: REST and SOAP WS, OAuth 1.0a and 2.0, JSON and XML
- Working with remote teams
- Test Driven Development: Specs2
- OLAP cubes configuration and data transformation routines
- Development primarily with Scala, Clojure/ClojureScript, JavaScript, Postfgresql, MySql, Mondrian, MDX, Play 2, SBT, Github, Heroku on GNU/Linux, Windows 7

Occupation or position held Dates

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

TYPE OF BUSINESS OR SECTOR

MAIN ACTIVITIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Technical Consultant

December 2011–Present Time

Obsidian Innovations Ltd., Espoo, Finland

Software Development and Consultancy

- Design and development of a financial analysis application
- Technology evaluation, business development, project planning
- Back-end architecture and development
- Developing dashboards and reports for daily trading
- Object-oriented programming, functional programming, software architecture, Test Driven Development, web development, cloud computing
- Development primarily with Scala, JavaFX, Java, Clojure, JavaScript, Maven, Play 2, JasperReports, Talend ETL, SBT, Github on GNU/Linux, Windows 7

Occupation or position held Dates

TYPE OF BUSINESS OF SECTOR

Technical Product Manager

March 2011-December 2011

Blancco Ltd., Helsinki and Joensuu, Finland

Development, distribution and maintenance of data destruction software systems

- Development of data destruction application
- Involvement in the gain of Data Security top certificates
- Working with remote development teams
- Development primarily with C++, Qt framework, GNU tool-chain, SVN, Trac

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD Dates

Main activities and responsibilities

Senior Software Engineer / Software Engineer

June 2007-February 2011

- Blancco Data Cleaner design and development
- Design and development of data destruction application (hardware communication, data destruction engine, remote API, graphical user interface)
- Object-oriented programming, architecture design, Test Driven Development, Continuous Integration
- Agile development using Scrum
- Enabling the adoption of Test Driven Development practices in the company
- Bringing latest industry trends in the product development process
- Working with remote development teams
- Development primarily with C, CVS, GNU tool-chain, Valgrind, Bash, Emacs, Linux Kernel 2.4-2.6, C++, Qt framework, GNU tool-chain, SVN, Trac

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD
DATES

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

TYPE OF BUSINESS OR SECTOR

MAIN ACTIVITIES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

Software Engineer

March 2007-May 2007

Speech and Image Processing Unit, Computer Science and Statistics Department, University of Joensuu, Finland

Development of a speech recognition application

- GUI development for a speech recognition application
- Object-oriented programming, architecture design
- Integration of different components
- Development primarily with C++, wxWidgets, SVN